# SIDDHESH THADESHWAR

 $siddhesht@outlook.in \mid \underline{+91-8898538569} \mid Mumbai, MH, India \mid \underline{linkedin.com/in/siddheshthadeshwar} \mid \underline{github.com/djsiddz}$ 

Innovative Technology Leader and Front-end Specialist with 9+ years of experience in software development. Synchronizing tech roadmaps with business goals for 5 projects, mentoring a team of 8, and creative problem-solving.

#### **SKILLS**

**Front-end:** React, Next.js, Astro, Angular, JavaScript, TypeScript, ES6, JSX, JSON, Web Applications, SASS/SCSS, CSS, HTML, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Styled Components, Bootstrap, HeadlessUI, UI Design, UX Research, Web Design, SPA (Single Page Applications), MPA (Multiple Page Applications),

Back-end: NodeJS, ExpressJS, KoaJS, TypeORM, Firebase, REST API, GraphQL,

MySQL, Postgres, Database Design, Schema Design, Zod, Supabase

Tools: Jira, Git, Gitlab, GitHub, Webpack, Figma, Photoshop, PageSpeed Insights

Soft Skills: Leadership, Technical Architecture, Team Management, Project Management, Mentoring,

Innovative, Adaptability, Flexibility, Avid Learner, Communication, Collaboration

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Square Yards, Mumbai

September 2021 – Present

## **Technology Lead**

- Architect the Frontend for 5 projects from scratch, based on the requirements & goals received from the stakeholders.
- Create monthly & weekly roadmaps for feature development & enhancements, across 4 projects.
- Hiring, mentoring & leading a team of 8 engineers across the stack in technologies like NextJS, React, NodeJS, KoaJS.
- Using Gitlab Issues & Milestones in an Agile manner for tracking, review, changelogs & user training, reducing time-to-deployment by 20% and achieving 70% decrease in post-deployment bugs.
- Implementing best coding practices to achieve 20-25% improvement in code modularity, efficiency, and reusability within the team.

Azuro (Acquired by Square Yards), Gurgaon & Mumbai

January 2020 - August 2021

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

- Developed an internal Web App using React, Bootstrap for the frontend, and Node.js, Koa & TypeORM for the backend, training a team of 15+ users across multiple geographies.
- Led the development of 2 business critical features in coordination with Mobile App Developers, for smooth user experience.
- Mentored 3 juniors and guided 3 peers during the development process by pair-programming.

Azuro, Mumbai

September 2019 - December 2019

#### **Senior Frontend Developer**

- Developed and re-wrote Web Apps from AngularJS to Angular 2.
- Performed migration to Angular 4, 6 & 8 for performance improvement and access to new capabilities of the framework.
- Led the development of new web apps and 35+ micro-sites.
- Conducted UX Research and created UI Designs for 5+ features using Figma.

#### **Frontend Developer**

- Transformed UI designs for 2 projects a Lead Management System & the company website.
- Conducted extensive UX research and added, removed, or improved app features, based on usage data tracking.
- Tech stack: AngularJS, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML.

Stringz Web & Graphics, Mumbai

November 2013 - August 2016

#### **Co-Founder & Web Initiatives Lead**

- Created Personal websites, Company Websites & Web Apps, along with SEO services for 10+ clients across industries.
- Supplied design services such as Brand Design & Logo Design to 5+ recurring clients.
- Catered to business requirements such as Visiting Cards, Letterheads, Brochures, Pamphlets, Stickers, and Packaging, from design to printing via vendors, for multiple clients.

# **PROJECTS**

### Data Intelligence Widgets | India, UAE (Dubai), Canada

- A widgets gallery with easy-to-understand insights on the real estate market.
- Support for cities, micro-markets, locations, & even project-level insights with multiple visualization options tabular, charts, 2D maps & 3D maps.
- Serving over 5M unique URLs through a mix of 20+ variants across three geographies India, UAE (Dubai) & Canada.
- Crunching data from multiple sources using AI & ML.
- Frontend Tech Stack: Next.js, MUI, ApexCharts, D3.js, and Cesium.

# **Data Intelligence Services | Link**

- A B2B SaaS product that can empower your Real Estate Business, help you move faster with informed decision making.
- Currently active services Title Search Reports, Desktop Valuation Reports, Physical Valuation Reports, Transaction Search.
- Frontend Tech Stack: Next.js, MUI

#### **EDUCATION**

Mithibai College, Mumbai | 2014 - 2016

Master Of Science, Computer Science

Mithibai College, Mumbai | 2011 - 2014

**Bachelor Of Science, Computer Science**